Guide to the Mark Miller and Benmarl Winery Collection
Miller, Mark and Benmarl Winery Collection
- Series IV. Newspaper Articles and other Publications
  - The Sunday Freeman: New Valley vintners verge on success (Chazy Dowaliby), November 1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - New York Times: Hudson Valley is offering ownership by the Vine (Frank Prial), June 1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Marlboro winemaker sees vineyards asnew industry for Hudson valley (Mary Paden) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Poughkeepsie Journal: It was a milestone day for Valley Wine industry (Jim Detjen), December 1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Times Herald: Once over (Barbara Bedell), July 1975 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Good local flavor found in Hudson River wines (Barbara Ensrud) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - New York Times: Keeping Benmarl, a Hudson valley vineyard, in grapes instead of quarter acre lots (Frank Prial), April 1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - New York Times: New York vines bear good news (Howard Goldberg), November 1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Manhattan Arts: "Mark Miller: The Return to Romance" (Beverly Barbour), October 1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - DayHops Newsguide: "Mark Miller, renaissance man", Fall 1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - From the stockpot: Benamrl Winery ready for the big stomp (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - American Wine Society Journal: An American Winemaker in Burgundy (Mark Miller), Winter 1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Sunday Cape Cod Times: Ex-illustrator creates a vineyard that anyone can join (Frank Prial), June 1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - House and Garden: "New York State Wine: The oldest wine making region in the country is growing fast" (Sandra Oddo), 1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Mid Hudson Leisure: "Review of Hudson valley wines by Sylvia Fine" (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Foreword Article by Michael Demarest in Avenue Magazine (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Ulster county's Benmarl offers top wines, June 1981 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Hudson Vine Rebirth (Joel Stashenko) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Farm Journal: Whatever happened to country wines (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Hudson valley grapes (Joseph Galu), September 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Hartford Courant: "Vineyard Investment: Fine Whines" (Colin McEnroe), October 1984 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Miller's Book weaves a spell: Review of " Wine - A Gentleman's Game" by Donna Boyle Schwartz, Editor of Evening News (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Forbes: Late Bloomer (Ellen Paris), May 1984 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - ArtScience: Galleries offer more than works of art to area residents, Fall 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Sketches by Mark Miller: Man and a Woman (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence of Miller with others (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Benmarl Vineyards Vigneron: Benmarl's historic sign vanishes (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Time: Shaking California's throne:, November 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Letters to Societe des Vignerons (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 140 Illustrations from the other world of Societe Des Vignerons (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Poughkeepsie Journal: Nixon dead at 81, April 1994 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    The Photograph published is the portrait by Mark Miller of Nixon
  - The Pennsylvania Grape Letter and Wine News: Wedding at Benmarl (2 copies), November-December 1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Includes wedding picture of Eric Miller
  - European Wine Growers, April 1982 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Includes Basic idea, Importing formula, Example and Advantages
  - Ulster County Agricultural News: New Winery Guide Available, August 1981 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - The Country Gentleman: The Emerging wines of America (William McClure), Autumn 1976 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Wine from the soil of Hudson valley (Mark Miller) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Wines and Vines: "A Vineyard Year": An ex-grower reflects, February 1984 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Newsweek: The Grape Escape, October 1977 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Benmarl Vineyards: A Manual for Home Winemakers (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Wine: Benmarl (Patrice Gourdin), April/ May 1976 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Benmarl Vineyards Vigneron: Official Wineletter of Benmarl Societe des Vignerons, Spring 1980 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Includes a rare photo of Mark Miller with his then day old grandson Bayen Lee Miller
  - Welcome to the world of Benmarl (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Includes a brief description of wines in Benmarl and some history of the grapes at Benmarl
  - A series of illustrations in color of various paintings (Box 5, Folder 14)
    1911 Pont De Passy And the Eiffel Tower (Marc Chagall)
    1894 The Finish (Louis Anquetin)
    1873 At the Zoological Gardens (Felix Bracquemond)
    1898 The Pond in the Tuileries (Auguste Lepere)
    1893 Le Cirque Corvi (Georges de Feure)
    1885 A Vist to the Museum (Edgar Degas)
    1906 Flying Kites, Montmartre (William Glackens)
    1901 Jardin [De] Paris (Pablo Picasso)
  - The 'Pope' who is revising our bible of sayings (Article by Ralph Graves and Illustrations by William Bramhall) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Sketches of Benmarl Vineyards by Mark Miller (3 copies) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - The New York Times, Art & Leisure: When These Two Chat, an Era is Speaking (Ben Brantley), September 1997 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Article on Christopher Plummer and Julie Harris
  - Smithsonian: Article on 'Parisians at play during the heady fin de siecle', August 1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Article on Benmarl being awarded by New York its Blue Ribbon for 1974 Chardonnay (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Harper's Bazaar: Sparkling Christmas Spirits, December 1977 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Signature: A New York Wine Town Back in Business (2 copies) (Frank Prial), May 1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - The New York Times: New yorkers Can Take Pride in Thier Thriving, Surprising Hudson Valley Wines (Frank Prial), November 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Los Angeles Herald Examiner: Quality growing at New York's Benmarl Vineyards (Anthony Dias Blue), August 1979 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Benmarl Vineyards Vigneron: Official Wineletter of the Benmarl Societe Des Vignerons, Winter 1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Includes article on Benmarl winery completing 10 years
  - Benmarl Vineyards Vigneron: Official Wineletter of the Benmarl Societe Des Vignerons, Autumn 1982 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Includes article on Miller's Benmarl Vineyards adventure completing 25 years
  - Structure and By Laws of the Benmarl Societe Des Vignerons (as amended 1970) (3 copies), 1971 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Benmarl Vineyards Vigneron: Official Wineletter of the Benmarl Societe Des Vignerons, Winter 1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Includes article " Societe praised by Governor Carey"
  - Color printouts of various articles regarding Benmarl that appeared in different magazines (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Good Living: New York is state of the grape: Visit it !, July 1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Decanter: Review of Mark Miller's book ' Wine - A Gentleman's Game', February 1985 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Lets join the gents: Gents Ltd (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - A Man And A Woman..And Wine (Mark Miller) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Photocopies of various articles that appeared in different newspapers and magazines (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Photocopies of various articles that appeared in different newspapers and magazines (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Many copies of "Illustrating an Era"
- Series V. Audio and Video
  - Interview given to WDST, February 1994 (Box 3)
  - Interview given to WOR, June 1994 (Box 3)
  - Benmarl Winery, October 1989; 912 (Box 3)
  - Conversation: Mark Miller (Benmarl), January 1993; 913 (Box 3)
  - NewsCenter 6 Out & About, September 2000; 914 (Box 3)
  - HVNeighbor: M.Miller, January 1998; 915 (Box 3)
  - Benmarl Winery: To Grace And Mark Miller, 916 (Box 3)
  - Hudson Valley Neighbor: Mark Miller, NewsCenter 6, October 1992; 917 (Box 3)
  - Hudson Valley Neighbor, Lisa Loeb "Firecracker", All things Financial, 918 (Box 3)
  - Crushing Season, 919 (Box 3)
  - Benmarl Winery Feature Done by Karen Hendren, Worldwide TV News, June 1998; 920 (Box 3)
  - Harvest Comments, 1992; 921 (Box 3)
  - Financial Corne, TCI of NewYork, March 1993; 922 (Box 3)
  - Maine in White "Black Bears", 923 (Box 3)
  - 7th Annual Fete Muguet, May 2000; 924 (Box 3)
  - Route Des Vins 2 New York, June 2002; 925 (Box 3)
  - Financial Corner, Mark Miller, March 1993; 926 (Box 3)
  - All Things Financial - Mark Miller, 927 (Box 3)
- Series VI. Posters, Publication materials, Miller Art work and Drawings
  - A vintage year for winemaking, October 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Text By Chris Farlekas Photos By Manny Fuchs
  - The Sunday Herald Post: Making Whisky in the Bluegrass, June 1930 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Includes view of the grounds, photo of Executive Staff
  - Publication materials (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Includes proof copies
  - Benmarl Vineyards Vigneron: Official Wineletter of the Benmarl Societe des Vignerons (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Spring Tasting
  - Papers related to Tasting of March 1978 vintage (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Papers related to Benmarl Winery for SDV Exhibit (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Benmarl Vineyards Artwork (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Benmarl Vineyards: New York Times Magazine Related Artwork (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Benmarl Vineyards: General operating papers, Subscription agreement copies, List of wines, Limited Partnership Agreement, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Includes projections for working capital deficit
  - Benmarl Vineyards: By Laws Booklet, Artwork and Photos (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Print copies of photographs of Mark Miller at Benmarl Vineyards (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - The Daily Freeman Poster: Articles related to Hudson Valley Wine, February 1970 (Box 4)
  - Benmarl Vineyards Founder's Family related photos and artwork (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Poster with articles on Aperitif wines and Hudson Valley Wines from Beverage Retailer Weekly(2 copies) (Box 4)
  - Poster with articles on Hudson Valley Wines from Beverage Retailer Weekly (Box 4)
  - Poster with article: "Harvest season begins in the vineyards" (Box 4)
  - Poster with article from Herald Tribune: "Festival with wine" (Box 4)
  - Benmarl Vineyards PMT Prints (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Benmarl Vineyards Farm Ads and Spray Information (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Benmarl Vineyards Hudson Valley Magazine related papers (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Benmarl Vineyards Avenue Reprint, Artwork and originals (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Includes NY Times story on Hudson Valley Wineries
  - Benmarl Vineyards Poster: Wine from the Soil of Marlboro..with the Soul of France (Box 4)
  - Various drawings, art work of Mark Miller to be used for advertising (Box 4, Folder 15)